# Sajankumar Vijayan

+31644961928 | <u>sajankumar.v@outlook.com</u> | Netherlands, Rachmaninovstraat 28, 1323NG, Almere | <a href="https://sajankumarv.com">https://sajankumarv.com</a> | github: <a href="https://github.com/sajanv88">https://github.com/sajanv88</a>

### **Summary**

Having 10+ years of experience building websites and applications. In those years I've worked with a wide range of clients from small startups to large companies across Asia, Europe and America. Working experience on projects that range from CMS websites to SaaS Apps has given me a great insight into all aspects of a project.

I am a dedicated and self-motivated developer who loves coding, open source, and the web platform. I love what I do and take great pride in all of my work. I'm always looking for the next challenge to create something incredible.

#### **Skills**

JavaScript & TypeScript - ECMA5/6/7, JavaScript, Typescript, React Js, Next Js, Node Js, Docker, AWS, kubernetes Jenkins, ¡Query, Express Js, webdriver.io, RXJS, Redux, Modern Modules pattern.

Java - Spring-boot, Rest Service Development, Maven.

Other Skills - HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind css, Responsive web design, SCSS, BEM, Postgres, Mongo dB, Web-pack, Gulp Collaborating and working a team environment via JIRA, GIT, CICD, Jenkins, AWS, Digital Ocean

#### Experience

Software Engineer III, Elsevier B.V

07/2019 -- present

I am working as a software engineer III at Elsevier B.V building new features And the maintaining Funding institution and NIAD-QE (scopus matching portal) product.

Tech Stack - React js, Next js, Typescript, Nodejs, Docker, AWS, Jenkins, react-testing-library, Jira, Java (Spring-boot), HTML5, SCSS, Tailwind css, Postgres database,

**Senior Consultant**, GeekSoft Consulting BV, Netherlands (contract position) 11/2018 -- 06/2019

I have been working for "KLM" client, which is best Airline Industry. My role and responsibilities are developing generic user interactive components

for career application and connect to various rest Apis inside the KLM network.

Tech Stack - Angular 6, Typescript, Nodejs, Docker, Mocha, Chai, Jira, Bitbucket, Java (Spring-boot), HTML5, SCSS (BEM), Postgres database

Senior Software Engineer, Accionlabs, Bangalore, Karnataka I worked for "RACKSPACE" client, which is one of the largest Cloud Computing services.

My role and responsibilities are to develop and maintain user interface application. The

01/2017-11/2018

application which I am working on is used on Rackspace cloud interface components which can be used by other Rackspace internal projects inside the company.

#Projects - Encore-origin, IPUI, VST, Encore-Account-UI, Gift-registry
Tech Stack - React JS, RXJS, Docker, Jenkins, CICD, Angular, Redux, JavaScript,
Babel, Nodejs, Mocha, Chai, Protractor, Karma, Jira, GIT, RestAPI Python (Flask),
MongoDB, HTML5, Less

Tech Lead, HCL Technologies, Chennai, Tamil Nadu

03/2016-09/2017

I worked for "CATERPILLAR" client, which is one of the largest American corporations. My role and responsibilities were to develop and maintain their existing web & mobile application for them. The application which I worked on was specialized in tracking and monitoring their machineries called "Assets" in all round the world via this application.

#Projects - PLW (Product Link Web), PLWM (Product Link web Mobile)

Tech Stack - Angularjs, Ionic framwork, Angular2, Typescript, JavaScript, Babel, Nodejs, Mocha, Chai, Karma, GIT, RestAPI Java, SQL, Mongodb

Software Engineer, Servion Global solution, Chennai, Tamil Nadu

12/2014-03/2016

I worked as a software engineer for the client Click Fox. My role and responsibilities were to develop their product called CEA. It was a web application based on big data platform and a suite of solutions that enable enterprises to get the most value out of each customer interaction across all channels. With its unique data infrastructure and proprietary algorithms, the Click Fox Experience Analytics (CEA) Platform connects all customer touch point data across enterprise systems to create transparency on the end-to-end Customer Journeys.

#Projects - Click-fox (Analytical Platform) Build for Verizon, T-mobile Honor & Awards: Spot Award 2015 for "Learning and innovation, collaboration, ownership, performance

Tech Stack - Angularjs, JavaScript, Jquery, Nodejs, Mocha, Chai, Jira, Tourtise HG, Java, Hadoop, HTML5, SCSS (BEM), Postgres, Mongodb

Software Developer, Digent Technologies, Chennai, Tamil Nadu

11/2012-07/2014

I worked as a software developer in Digent Technologies, my role and responsibilities were to develop the gaming portal web application and standalone software's.

#Projects - Game Management software (in-house), Casino Management, 3-reel slots (Game), Horse-bet multiplayer game.

2011-2012

Tech Stack - Angularjs, JavaScript, Jquery, Jira, SVN/GIT, Java, HTML5, Adobe Flash ActionScript 3, Flex 3, MYSQL

2010-2011

Software Developer, DCKAP Technologies, Chennai, Tamil Nadu Software Developer, ITutor, Chennai, Tamil Nadu

## Education

**Bachelor of Science, Visual Communication**, University of Madras, Chennai, Tamil Nadu [NIIT, Certified Java web developer - 2011]

2006-2009

## Language

Communication Skills - English (Fluent), Malayalam (Native speaker), Tamil (Native speaker)